Register of the Charles F. Darlington papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- League of Nations File, 1930-1933, undated
  - Correspondence, 1930-1931, undated
    - Riga, 1931 March 20 (Box-folder 5: 109)
    - van Rijn, F. J. L., Dr., 1931 February 13-23 (Box-folder 5: 110)
    - Roberts, George E., 1930 July 1 - 1931 September 8 (Box-folder 5: 111)
    - Roberts, H. A., 1931 September 18 (Box-folder 5: 112)
    - Rodd, Francis, 1931 January 30 (Box-folder 5: 113)
    - Rodenbach, Constantin, 1931 January 23-April 30 (Box-folder 5: 114)
    - Romania, 1930 June 26-November 15 (Box-folder 5: 115)
    - Rose, Adam, 1931 February 13-25 (Box-folder 5: 116)
    - Rueff, Jacques, 1931 July 9-21 (Box-folder 5: 117)
    - Rygg, N., 1931 July 9 (Box-folder 5: 118)
    - Salvador, 1930 August 28 - 1931 January 23 (Box-folder 5: 119)
    - Santo Domingo, 1930 June 2 (Box-folder 5: 120)
    - Schmidt, A., 1931 July 21 (Box-folder 5: 121)
    - Schnabel, 1931 June 10 (Box-folder 5: 122)
    - Schoell, 1930 July 18 (Box-folder 5: 123)
    - Schulz, Dr. Bruno, 1930 September 8-13 (Box-folder 5: 124)
    - Secretan, J., 1930 June 26 (Box-folder 5: 125)
    - Sevensma, 1931 February 12-July 21 (Box-folder 5: 126)
    - Siam, 1930 June 2-July 14 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Sidler, Alb., 1931 September 18 (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - Singer, Paul, 1930 June 8 - 1931 July 21 (Box-folder 6: 3)
    - Snelders, Anna, 1930 June 27-July 25 (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - Sommer, Oscar, 1931 March 9-September 8 (Box-folder 6: 5)
    - South Africa, 1930 June 26 (Box-folder 6: 6)
    - Southern Rhodesia, 1930 June 2 (Box-folder 6: 7)
    - Spain, 1930 July 18-September 8 (Box-folder 6: 8)
    - Spiller, 1930 November 3 (Box-folder 6: 9)
    - Sprague, 1930 July 12-September 25 (Box-folder 6: 10)
    - Stock Exchange, 1930 July 18 (Box-folder 6: 11)
    - Straits settlements, 1930 June 26-July 5 (Box-folder 6: 12)
    - Strakosch, Sir Henry, 1930 July 29 - 1931 July 21 (Box-folder 6: 13)
    - Sugar, 1930 July 1 (Box-folder 6: 14)
      Note to "Monsieur Le Secretaire Przenuyala Cukrowniczego" (in French), reflects original order and alphabetization.
    - Suvich, Fulvio, et. al, 1930 June 27, undated (Box-folder 6: 15)
    - Switzerland, 1930 October 8-31 (Box-folder 6: 16)
    - Taussig, Professor F. W., 1930 July 29 - September 8 (Box-folder 6: 17)
    - Terhaar, Dr. Jost, 1931 February 12 (Box-folder 6: 18)
    - Tismer, Dr. Alfred, 1931 February 12 (Box-folder 6: 19)
    - Treasurer, 1931 January 19 (Box-folder 6: 20)
    - Treybal, Bohumir, 1931 February 12-13 (Box-folder 6: 21)
    - Trip, L. J. A., Dr., 1930 July 25 - 1931 July 21 (Box-folder 6: 22)
    - Tsouderos, 1931 July 9 (Box-folder 6: 23)
    - Tsushima, Juichi, 1930 June 27-August 23 (Box-folder 6: 24)
    - Turkey, 1930 August 1-September 8 (Box-folder 6: 25)
    - Uruguay, 1930 August 28-September 26 (Box-folder 6: 26)
    - Valeurs Mobilieres, 1930 July 18 (Box-folder 6: 27)
    - Venezuela, 1930 June 26 (Box-folder 6: 28)
    - Victor, Hugo, 1930 November 15 (Box-folder 6: 29)
    - Vocke, Dr. Wilhelm, 1930 June 2-August 18 (Box-folder 6: 30)
    - Wagon-Lits, 1930 September 25 (Box-folder 6: 31)
    - Walcher, Guido, 1931 May 26 (Box-folder 6: 32)
    - Wallenberg, Marcus, 1930 June 27-August 23 (Box-folder 6: 33)
    - Watt, Arthur C., 1930 November 15 (Box-folder 6: 34)
    - Watteau, 1931 February 13-June 18 (Box-folder 6: 35)
    - West Africa (British), 1930 June 26-August 18 (Box-folder 6: 36)
    - West Africa (French), 1930 June 27-July 5 (Box-folder 6: 37)
    - Williams, Sir John Fischer, et. al, 1931 June 10 (Box-folder 6: 38)
    - Williamson, Sir Walter J. F., 1930 June 27 - 1931 June 18 (Box-folder 6: 39)
    - Wilson, Hugh R., 1931 April 8-16 (Box-folder 6: 40)
    - Yugoslavia, 1930 June 26 (Box-folder 6: 41)
    - Yumoto, T., 1931 February 28 (Box-folder 6: 42)
    - Yung, Guido (Guido Jung), 1931 July 21 (Box-folder 6: 43)
  - Photographs, undated (Box-folder 6: 44)
  - Printed matter, 1933 January 20 (Box-folder 6: 45)
- Bank for International Settlements File, 1931-1937, undated
  - Correspondence, 1931 September-1933 November, undated
    Contains general correspondence between Darlington and various European economic and financial advisors. Also contains correspondence between Darlington and acquaintances in the United States discussing the stock market crash of 1929 and subsequent economic policies of the New Deal. Maintains original order.
    - American Bureau of Metal Statistics, 1932 November 29 (Box-folder 6: 46)
    - Basel-Electricity, 1932 February 25 (Box-folder 6: 47)
    - de Bordes, Dr. J. van Walre, 1932 August 11 (Box-folder 6: 48)
    - Brabourne, 1932 January 28-February 9 (Box-folder 6: 49)
    - Brechya-Vauthier, 1932 January 4-8 (Box-folder 6: 50)
    - Brownwell, Francis H., 1932 January 28-March 1 (Box-folder 6: 51)
    - Bruce, Edward, 1933 June 14 (Box-folder 6: 52)
    - Colenutt, 1932 April 28, undated (Box-folder 6: 53)
    - Cunard, 1933 February 1 (Box-folder 6: 54)
    - Darlington, Gilbert, 1932 November 29 (Box-folder 6: 55)
    - Davis, Norman, 1932 November 10 (Box-folder 6: 56)
    - La Defense Automobile et Sportive, 1933 June 20 (Box-folder 6: 57)
    - Debevoise, Douglass, 1932 January 4 - 1933 January 27 (Box-folder 6: 58)
    - Douanes, 1932 January 12 - 1933 November 8 (Box-folder 6: 59)
    - Dreyfus, Armand, 1933 September 28 (Box-folder 6: 60)
    - Ehinger, A., 1932 September 14 (Box-folder 6: 61)
    - Emerson, Harrington, 1932 January 28 (Box-folder 6: 62)
    - Felkin, A. E., 1932 June 23 (Box-folder 6: 63)
    - Galantiere, Lewis, 1933 July 27 (Box-folder 6: 64)
    - Gardner, Walter R., 1932 December 2 - 1933 January 4 (Box-folder 6: 65)
    - Godard, 1932 May 3 (Box-folder 6: 66)
    - Goodwin, 1933 June 10 (Box-folder 6: 67)
    - Goppelsroeder-Sarasin, E., 1932 October 3 (Box-folder 6: 68)
    - Hammond, John Hays, 1932 January 28-March 1 (Box-folder 6: 69)
    - Hilgerdt, F., 1932 March 1 (Box-folder 6: 70)
    - Hopper, Bruce, 1931 September 23 (Box-folder 6: 71)
    - International Chamber of Commerce, 1932 January 28-February 13 (Box-folder 6: 72)
    - Iselin, Dr. Felix, 1932 April 17 - 1933 October 6 (Box-folder 6: 73)
    - Jacobssen, 1933 May 19-July 27 (Box-folder 6: 74)
    - Leverich, Henry, 1932 February 9 (Box-folder 6: 75)
    - Loveday, A., 1933 April 22 (Box-folder 6: 76)
    - Mant, Sir Reginald, 1932 January 8 (Box-folder 6: 77)
    - Mayhofer, 1932 February 9 (Box-folder 6: 78)
    - Meyer, Robert, 1932 December 7 - 1933 June 27 (Box-folder 6: 79)
    - Mlynarski, Dr. Feliks, 1932 January 8-18 (Box-folder 6: 80)
    - Mocatta and Goldsmid, 1932 January 8 (Box-folder 6: 81)
    - de Morant, 1932 October 28 (Box-folder 6: 82)
    - Morgan, Junius, 1932 February 12-March 1 (Box-folder 6: 83)
    - Myers, Denys P., 1932 March 1 - 1933 October 23 (Box-folder 6: 84)
    - National City Bank, 1931 September 18 - 1932 March 1 (Box-folder 6: 85)
    - New York Stock Exchange, 1931 September 18 (Box-folder 6: 86)
    - Pasvolsky, Leo, 1933 February 27 (Box-folder 6: 87)
    - Personnel Office - League, 1932 February 9 (Box-folder 6: 88)
    - Police (Basel), 1932 September 2 (Box-folder 6: 89)
    - Porters, 1933 February 25 (Box-folder 6: 90)
    - Potts, Frederic A., 1932 May 3 (Box-folder 6: 91)
    - Pratt, Irving, 1933 June 17 (Box-folder 6: 92)
    - Premchand, Maneklal, 1933 January 4-February 27 (Box-folder 6: 93)
    - Roncalgi, 1932 November 3 (Box-folder 6: 94)
    - Rosenborg, A., 1933 April 22 (Box-folder 6: 95)
    - Sarasin, A., 1933 April 26 (Box-folder 6: 96)
    - Schnabel, Frits, 1932 February 12 (Box-folder 6: 97)
    - Shields, 1933 August 5 (Box-folder 6: 98)
    - Silver Association, 1932 January 28-March 1 (Box-folder 6: 99)
    - Streit, Clarence, 1933 January 21-July 27 (Box-folder 6: 100)
    - Sverljuga, Dr. Stanko, 1932 June 15 (Box-folder 6: 101)
    - Tirana, Rifat, 1932 February 23-March 1 (Box-folder 6: 102)
    - U.S. Printing Office, 1932 January 28 (Box-folder 6: 103)
    - U.S. Superintendent of Documents, 1932 February 12 (Box-folder 6: 104)
    - Vernon-Grauer, 1933 November 8 (Box-folder 6: 105)
    - Willard, Charles H., 1933 June 20 (Box-folder 6: 106)
    - Williamson, Walter J. F., 1932 February 9 (Box-folder 6: 107)
    - de Wolf, Francis Colt, 1932 March 1 (Box-folder 6: 108)
    - Yugoslavia, 1932 June 17 (Box-folder 6: 109)
    - Zollinspektor, 1932 December 21 (Box-folder 6: 110)
  - Memoranda, 1932-1933, undated
    Contains official memos credited to the Monetary and Economic Department of the Bank for International Settlements. Maintains original order and separation of materials for the "World Economic Conference."
    - General, 1932 February 5-December 20, undated (Box-folder 6: 111, 7: 1)
    - "World Economic Conference,", 1932 October 19 - 1933 March 12, undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Printed matter, 1937 (Box-folder 7: 3)
- Department of State File, 1934-1939
  - Correspondence, 1934-1939
    - Briggs, Edith, 1938 December 28 - 1939 January 7 (Box-folder 7: 4)
    - Conolly, F. C., 1934 May 28 (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - Ezekiel, Mordecai, 1934 August 23 (Box-folder 7: 6)
    - Loveday, A., 1934 August 21 (Box-folder 7: 7)
    - Marvin, Mrs. Langdon P., 1939 January 17-19 (Box-folder 7: 8)
    - Myers, Denys P., 1934 June 27 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Speeches and writings, circa 1936, 1938, undated
    - "Chicago Address Notes,", undated (Box-folder 7: 10)
    - "The Most-Favored Nation Principle and Its Application by the United States in Connection with the Reciprocal Trade Agreements" (report), circa 1936 (Box-folder 7: 11)
    - "The Reciprocal Trade Agreements Program" (speech given at Kansas City), 1938 November (Box-folder 7: 12)
      Includes related press coverage and correspondence.
  - Memorandum, 1938 March 11 (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - Printed matter, 1938 March 23-July 5 (Box-folder 7: 14)
- United Nations File, 1945
  Contains materials from the United Nations Conference on International Organization, 1945 May-June. Includes social invitations, photographs, seating charts, attendee information, and fascimile of the proposed text of the UN Charter in five languages.
  - Correspondence (social invitations and events), 1945 May-June (Box-folder 7: 15)
  - Photographs, 1945 (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - Printed matter, 1945 (Box-folder 7: 17-18; 8: 1)
- Socony Vacuum Oil/Mobil Oil File, 1952-1960
  - Memoranda, 1952 September 25-October 17 (Box-folder 8: 2-3)
    Includes internal reports titled "Accepted Oil Agreement," "Currency Arrangements with the British Government," and "Soviet Oil."
  - Travel, 1952 November-1960 February
    Contains notes, reports, accounting statements, printed matter, and official correspondence relating to business trips taken by Darlington as a member of the Socony Vacuum/Mobil Oil Corporation. Maintains original organization and file titles when possible.
    - Correspondence, 1952 November 12-1953 January 30 (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - 1953 (Box-folder 8: 5)
      - Qatar, 1953 February 10-12
      - Saudia Arabia, 1953 February 13-15
      - Kuwait, 1953 February 16-17
      - Basrah, 1953 February 18-19
      - Baghdad, 1953 February 20-22
      - Rome and Naples, 1953 February 23-28
    - Tehran, 1955 May 21-29, undated (Box-folder 8: 6-7)
    - Kuwait, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 8: 8-10)
    - France, 1960 January 27-February 1 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - Printed matter, 1952, undated
    - Thirty Inch Pipeline Inauguration, 1952 November (Box-folder 8: 12)
    - Maps, undated (Box-folder 9: 1)
- Campaigns and Elections File, 1956-1960, undated
  - Supervisor-Bedford, 1957-1958, undated
    Contains notes, correspondence, and campaign materials related to Darlington's unsuccessful run for Supervisor of the Town of Bedford, New York in 1957.
    - Correspondence, 1957 September 27-November 21, undated (Box-folder 9: 2)
    - Speeches and writings, 1957-1958, undated (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - Notes, 1957 June 15, undated (Box-folder 9: 4)
      Includes records of and notes made about phone conversations with various voters and campaign donors.
    - Receipts, 1957 November 26-28 (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - Printed matter, 1957 September 9 - 1958 February 20, undated (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - 1956 National, 1956-1957
    Contains material related to Darlington's involvement with the Westchester County Democratic Committee and Adlai Stevenson's presidential campaign during the 1956 presidential election. Also includes speeches Darlington wrote for Stevenson.
    - Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 9: 7-8)
    - Speeches and writings, 1956 March-October, undated (Box-folder 9: 9)
      Includes "Memorandum on the H-Bomb Issue," dated 1956 October 30.
    - Notes, 1956 June-October, undated (Box-folder 9: 10)
    - Printed matter, 1956 April - 1957 February (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - 1960 National, 1960 July-December, undated
    Contains material related to Darlington's work with the Westchester County Democratic Committee and the Kennedy-Johnson campaign in the 1960 presidential election, especially the campaign in New York. Also includes speeches Darlington wrote for Kennedy.
    - Correspondence, 1960 July 18-December 21, undated (Box-folder 9: 12)
    - Meeting and prospect notes, 1960 August-September, undated (Box-folder 9: 13)
    - Event invitations and materials, 1960 September 27-November 8, undated (Box-folder 9: 14)
      Contains invitations to fundraisers and events involving Eleanor Roosevelt and Adlai Stevenson, as well as agendas and other printed materials for the events.
    - Printed matter, 1960 September 4-October 19, undated (Box-folder 9: 15)
  - 1960 Westchester, 1960 August-November
    Contains material related to Darlington's work with the Westchester County Democratic Committee during the 1960 state and local elections in Westchester, New York.
    - Correspondence, 1960 August-September (Box-folder 9: 16)
    - Speeches and writings, 1960 August 1-November 21 (Box-folder 9: 17)
      Drafts of various untitled speeches written by Darlington.
    - Printed matter, 1960 August (Box-folder 9: 18)
- United Nations Ambassador to Gabon File, 1949-1985, undated
  - Correspondence, 1961-1985, undated
    - General, 1962-1967, undated (Box-folder 9: 19)
    - "Bedford-Gabon Committee,", 1961-1963 (Box-folder 9: 20)
    - "Burundi and Rio Muni,", 1962 July 1-September 18 (Box-folder 9: 21)
    - "Gabon, Letters,", 1961-1969 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - "Letters and notes relating to my quest for an Ambassadorship and some correspondence received after my appointment,", 1960 August 26 - 1961 September 18 (Box-folder 10: 2)
    - "Letters from Africa,", 29 August 1970 - 1973 March 19 (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - "Letters from Libreville,", 1962-1985, undated (Box-folder 10: 4)
      Includes correspondence with President of Gabon Leon Mba.
    - "Some Later Correspondence,", 1961-1971, undated (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - Embassy event notes, invitations, and related correspondence, 1961-1964, undated (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - Speeches and writings, 1963-1964, undated (Box-folder 10: 7)
    Includes related correspondence.
    - "Notes for Bedford Talk,", undated
    - "A Gabonese Mvette," interpreted from Fang into French by the Deputy Jacques Biyogho and Dr. Joseph-Marie Aubian, transcribed and edited in English by Charles Darlington, 1963 September 5
    - "The Damage to American Leadership" (unpublished draft), 1964 September
    - "The American Spirit" (unpublished draft), 1964 September 16
    - "On Communism" (unpublished draft), 1964 September 28
    - "On Youth" (unpublished draft), 1964 September 28
    - "The World of Reality" (unpublished draft), 1964 September 28
  - Notes and memoranda, 1961-1964, undated (Box-folder 10: 8)
  - Speeches and writings by others, 1949-1967, undated (Box-folder 10: 9-10)
    Contains collected speeches and writings by Albert Schweitzer as well as correspondence between Darlington and Schweitzer after the two met in Gabon.
  - Photographs, circa 1964 (Box-folder 10: 11)
  - Printed matter, 1961-1968, undated (Box-folder 11: 1-3)
    Various magazines and journals relating to Gabon and Africa. Also includes four issues of L'Effort Gabonais dated 1963 September-1964 May.
- Photographs, undated (Box-folder 11: 4)
- Printed Matter, 1941-1960, undated (Box-folder 11: 5-6)